<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on Avatar Optimizer (1.8.6)</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on Avatar Optimizer (1.8.6)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic Concepts</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/basic-concept/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/basic-concept/</guid><description>Basic Concepts of Avatar Optimizer # This page describes the basic concepts of Avatar Optimizer.
What is Avatar Optimizer? # Avatar Optimizer is a non-destructive tool that helps you optimize your avatar. This tool is initially designed for VRChat avatars, but it might be usable for other Avatars supported by NDMF.
Non-destructive means (in Avatar Optimizer):
You don&amp;rsquo;t have to unpack your prefab to apply Avatar Optimizer. What you have to do is adding component.</description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/faq/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions # Here is the list of frequently asked questions about Avatar Optimizer. If you have some other questions, please feel free to ask on the GitHub Discussions, NDMF Discord or Fediverse (Misskey / Mastodon). I&amp;rsquo;m usually use Japanese, but you can ask me with English.
The behavior or appearance of the avatar is changed when using AAO Trace and Optimize component # If the behavior or appearance of the avatar is changed when using AAO Trace and Optimize component, it is always a bug unless you depend on bugs in other components of Avatar Optimizer.</description></item><item><title>Changelog</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/changelog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/changelog/</guid><description>Changelog # All notable changes to this project are documented in this page.
The format is based on Keep a Changelog.
1.8.6 - 2025-02-14 # Fixed # Error when we manually configure Merge Skinned Mesh for face mesh along with Trace and Optimize #1396 Missing localization for copy enablement animation related errors #1397 1.8.5 - 2025-02-05 # Fixed # Component Validation Errors doesn&amp;rsquo;t have error source component information #1390 liltoon Angel Ring MatCap settings broken #1391 1.</description></item></channel></rss>