<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docs on Avatar Optimizer (1.7.6)</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on Avatar Optimizer (1.7.6)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic Concepts</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/basic-concept/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/basic-concept/</guid><description>Basic Concepts of Avatar Optimizer # This page describes the basic concepts of Avatar Optimizer.
What is Avatar Optimizer? # Avatar Optimizer is a tool that helps you optimize your avatar. This tool is initially designed for VRChat avatars, but it might be usable for other Avatars supported by NDMF.
Non-VRChat avatar support is completely community-based and may not be supported by the Avatar Optimizer dev team.
What is the goal of Avatar Optimizer?</description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/faq/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions # Here is the list of frequently asked questions about Avatar Optimizer. If you have some other questions, please feel free to ask on the GitHub Discussions or on Fediverse (Misskey / Mastodon). I&amp;rsquo;m usually use Japanese, but you can ask me with English.
The behavior or appearance of the avatar is changed when using AAO Trace and Optimize component # If the behavior or appearance of the avatar is changed when using AAO Trace and Optimize component, it is always a bug unless you depend on bugs in other components of Avatar Optimizer.</description></item><item><title>Changelog</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/changelog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/en/docs/changelog/</guid><description>Changelog # All notable changes to this project are documented in this page.
The format is based on Keep a Changelog.
1.7.6 - 2024-06-17 # Fixed # BlendTree with NormalizedBlendValues Broken with MergeBlendTree #1096 Remove Zero Sized Polygon may remove small polygons #1098 1.7.5 - 2024-06-10 # Added # Warnings for bad API Usages #1091 Changed # Ignore floating point precision error in Merge PhysBone #1086 Animation Warning of Merge Skinned Mesh will not generated if source Renderer is not animated #1087 Expression Parameters are now considered as a part of Avatar Dynamics Parameter destination #1089 Relax condition for scaled evenly check #1092 Trace and Optimize will merge more bones than before.</description></item></channel></rss>