<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on Avatar Optimizer (1.6.5-beta.1)</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on Avatar Optimizer (1.6.5-beta.1)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Changelog</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/changelog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/changelog/</guid><description>Changelog # All notable changes to this project are documented in this page.
The format is based on Keep a Changelog.
1.6.5-beta.1 - 2023-12-28 # Changed # AvatarOptimizer now uses ErrorReporting API of NDMF instead of our own API #805 Fixed # Fix support for UniVRM components #802 1.6.4 - 2023-12-10 # 1.6.4-beta.1 - 2023-12-10 # Fixed # Error with generic avatar in 2022 #794 Assertion Error in some rare case #795 1.</description></item><item><title>Avatar Global Components</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/component-kind/avatar-global-components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/component-kind/avatar-global-components/</guid><description>Avatar Global Components # Avatar Global Component is a kind of component which should be added to an avatar root and applied to whole avatar.
The &amp;ldquo;avatar root&amp;rdquo; is the GameObject at the top of the avatar hierarchy. For example, in the case of a VRChat avatar, the &amp;ldquo;avatar root&amp;rdquo; is the GameObject that has the VRC Avatar Descriptor component.
If you add any Avatar Global Components to anything other than the avatar root, you&amp;rsquo;ll see error on the inspector and will not have any effect.</description></item><item><title>Trace And Optimize</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/trace-and-optimize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/trace-and-optimize/</guid><description>Trace And Optimize # Previously known as Automatic Configuration
This component will trace your avatar and optimize your avatar automatically. You can enable/disable some automatic optimization features with checkboxes.
This component should be added to an avatar root. (Kind: Avatar Global Component)
Currently the following optimizations are applied automatically.
Automatically Freeze Blend Shape
Automatically freezes unused BlendShapes in animation or else. Remove unused Objects
By scanning animation etc., automatically removes unused Objects (e.</description></item><item><title>UnusedBonesByReferencesTool</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/unused-bones-by-references-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/unused-bones-by-references-tool/</guid><description>UnusedBonesByReferencesTool # Marks it as EditorOnly that bones referenced only from EditorOnly meshes.
This component should be added to an avatar root. (Kind: Avatar Global Component)
This component is obsolete. You should use Remove unused Objects of Trace and Optimize instead. This component will never get algorithm improvements. This is port of UnusedBonesByReferencesTool by Narazaka but run at build time.</description></item><item><title>Edit Skinned Mesh Components</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/component-kind/edit-skinned-mesh-components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/component-kind/edit-skinned-mesh-components/</guid><description>Edit Skinned Mesh Components # Edit Skinned Mesh Component is a kind of component which should be added to a GameObject which has a SkinnedMeshRenderer component, and applies some modification to the SkinnedMeshRenderer.
There are two sub-kinds.
Source Component # This kind of component will produce Mesh and some other properties of SkinnedMeshRenderer.
Following components are Source Edit Skinned Mesh Component.
MergeSkinnedMesh
This component will produce mesh from other (Skinned)MeshRenderers.</description></item><item><title>Merge Skinned Mesh</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/merge-skinned-mesh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/merge-skinned-mesh/</guid><description>Merge Skinned Mesh # Merges one or more SkinnedMeshRenderer and MeshRenderers into one SkinnedMeshRenderer.
This component should be added to a new GameObject which has a SkinnedMeshRenderer component without Mesh specified. (Kind: Source Edit Skinned Mesh Component)
Benefits # Merging SkinnedMeshRenderer will reduce number of deforming mesh (skinning). Also, it can reduce material slots using the same material, so we can reduce rendering cost.
Notes # This component makes it impossible to turn meshes on and off individually on animations, but material-related animations will work without modification.</description></item><item><title>Freeze BlendShape</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/freeze-blendshape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/freeze-blendshape/</guid><description>Freeze BlendShape # Freeze &amp;amp; remove BlendShape from the mesh.
This component should be added to a GameObject which has a SkinnedMeshRenderer component. (Kind: Modifying Edit Skinned Mesh Component)
Benefits # Freezing &amp;amp; removing BlendShapes has the following benefits.
For BlendShapes with non-zero weight, freezing BlendShapes will reduce processing cost. Even if the weight is zero, removing BlendShapes will reduce the size of avatars. Notes # By freezing BlendShape, the weights cannot be changed on Animation.</description></item><item><title>Merge ToonLit Material</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/merge-toonlit-material/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/merge-toonlit-material/</guid><description>Merge ToonLit Material # Merge VRChat/Mobile/Toon Lit materials to one material by packing texture manually.
This component should be added to a GameObject which has a SkinnedMeshRenderer component. (Kind: Modifying Edit Skinned Mesh Component)
This component currently only supports VRChat/Mobile/Toon Lit because I believe there are big demands but I may add support for other shaders. (also for third-party shaders) If you want other shader support, please write a issue</description></item><item><title>Remove Mesh By BlendShape</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/remove-mesh-by-blendshape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/remove-mesh-by-blendshape/</guid><description>Remove Mesh By BlendShape # Remove vertices transformed by specified BlendShape and their polygons.
This component should be added to a GameObject which has a SkinnedMeshRenderer component. (Kind: Modifying Edit Skinned Mesh Component)
Benefits # By removing polygons which are hidden by clothes or something, you can reduce rendering cost, BlendShape processing cost, etc. without affecting the appearance so much. You can use this component to easily remove polygons with BlendShapes for shrinking parts of the body, which many avatars have.</description></item><item><title>Remove Mesh in Box</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/remove-mesh-in-box/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/remove-mesh-in-box/</guid><description>Remove Mesh in Box # Remove some polygons in any of specified boxes.
This component should be added to a GameObject which has a SkinnedMeshRenderer component. (Kind: Modifying Edit Skinned Mesh Component)
Benefits # By removing polygons which are hidden by clothes or something, you can reduce rendering cost, BlendShape processing cost, etc. without affecting the appearance so much.
Settings # Adjust the value to add box. For each box, you can change the center Position, Size, and Rotation of the box.</description></item><item><title>Clear Endpoint Position</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/clear-endpoint-position/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/clear-endpoint-position/</guid><description>Clear Endpoint Position # This component will replace EndpointPosition to 0 with adding _EndPhysBone GameObject.
This component should be added to a GameObject which has PhysBone Components.
This component doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any configuration for now but there&amp;rsquo;s one button on the view. Clicking Apply and Remove component will applies this operation and removes this component. This may be useful for developing avatars.</description></item><item><title>Merge Bone</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/merge-bone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/merge-bone/</guid><description>Merge Bone # If you add this component to some GameObject, the GameObject will be removed and merged to parent GameObject. Also, if some other components are attached to the target GameObject, they will be removed too.
If the parent GameObject also have Merge Bone component, two GameObjects are merged to their further parent GameObject.
All children of GameObject where this component is applied will belong to parent of this GameObject.</description></item><item><title>Merge PhysBone</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/merge-physbone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/merge-physbone/</guid><description>Merge PhysBone # This component merges multiple PhysBone Components into one Component with MultiChildType == Ignore.
This component should be added to a new GameObject.
Settings # Components # The list of PhysBone Component.
Drop to None element at the bottom to add PhysBone and reset to None to remove from the list.
Overrides # Below the configurations, there&amp;rsquo;s configurations like VRCPhysBone. For each property, you may select Copy to copy value from source property (only available if values from the sources are same) or Override to set new value instead.</description></item><item><title>Remove Zero Sized Polygon</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/remove-zero-sized-polygon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/remove-zero-sized-polygon/</guid><description>Remove Zero Sized Polygon # Remove polygons whose area are zero.
This component should be added to a GameObject which has a SkinnedMeshRenderer component.
Since this component works very late in the build process, this component is NOT Modifying Edit Skinned Mesh Component.
Adding this component to the SkinnedMeshRenderers to be merged by Merge Skinned Mesh component has no effect.
Benefits # By removing polygons whose area are zero, you can reduce rendering cost.</description></item><item><title>Make Children</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/make-children/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/reference/make-children/</guid><description>Make Children # These specified objects will be the children of this GameObject at build time.
This component is deprecated.
This function is not related to avatar optimization, so this component will be replaced by one in a currently planned non-destructive Avatar Modification Utils.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/404.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/404.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Basic Usage</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/tutorial/basic-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/tutorial/basic-usage/</guid><description>Basic Usage # Use Automatic Optimization # There are several optimizations which can be performed automatically for Avatars.
Removing Unused BlendShapes(Shape Keys)1 For BlendShapes with non-zero weight, freezing BlendShapes will reduce processing cost. Even if the weight is zero, removing BlendShapes will reduce the size of avatars. Removing unused Behaviours such as PhysBones If there are enabled PhysBones which do not need to be swayed (e.g., the swaying target mesh is always disabled), extra computational cost is caused.</description></item><item><title>Make your components compatible with Avatar Optimizer</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/developers/make-your-components-compatible-with-aao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/developers/make-your-components-compatible-with-aao/</guid><description>Make your components compatible with Avatar Optimizer # This page describes the following two things.
When can components be incompatible with Avatar Optimizer? How to improve the compatibility? If you have some question, please feel free to ask @anatawa12@misskey.niri.la on fediverse.
When can components be incompatible with Avatar Optimizer? # If your components are on the avatar and still exist when Avatar Optimizer processes it, your components can be incompatible with Avatar Optimizer.</description></item></channel></rss>