<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>For Developers on Avatar Optimizer (1.7.4)</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/developers/</link><description>Recent content in For Developers on Avatar Optimizer (1.7.4)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/developers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Asset Description</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/developers/asset-description/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/developers/asset-description/</guid><description>Asset Description # Asset Description is the file to provide information of your assets for Avatar Optimizer.
Why Asset Description is needed # Avatar Optimizer has to know about all existing components in the Avatar to remove unnecessary ones.
Avatar Optimizer v1.6.0 added document to make your components compatible with AAO and API for it, but for in-place modification tools that do not process on build, it&amp;rsquo;s a little bit complicated to remove components by IVRCSDKPreprocessAvatarCallback instead of Avatar Optimizer.</description></item><item><title>Distributing Prefabs</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/developers/distributing-prefabs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/developers/distributing-prefabs/</guid><description>Distributing Prefabs # Avatar Optimizer mey help you making your assets lightweight and optimized. Here are some recommendations for how to distribute prefabs that depend on Avatar Optimizer.
Guide your users to the official distribution of Avatar Optimizer # Since Avatar Optimizer is published under MIT License, redistribution is allowed. However, I strongly recommend you to guide your users to the official distribution of Avatar Optimizer.
Your unofficial distribution of Avatar Optimizer may be outdated.</description></item><item><title>Make your components compatible with Avatar Optimizer</title><link>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/developers/make-your-components-compatible-with-aao/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpm.anatawa12.com/avatar-optimizer/beta/en/docs/developers/make-your-components-compatible-with-aao/</guid><description>Make your components compatible with Avatar Optimizer # This page describes the following two things.
When can components be incompatible with Avatar Optimizer? How to improve the compatibility? If you have some question, please feel free to ask @anatawa12@misskey.niri.la on fediverse.
When can components be incompatible with Avatar Optimizer? # If your components are on the avatar and still exist when Avatar Optimizer processes it, your components can be incompatible with Avatar Optimizer.</description></item></channel></rss>